<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<post>
  <title>Using the Twitter Bootstrap Template with ASP.NET MVC 4 Requires jQuery Update</title>
  <slug>using-the-twitter-bootstrap-template-with-aspnet-mvc-4-requires-jquery-update</slug>
  <pubDate>2012-07-29T18:05:00.000Z</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2019-01-12T23:08:58.826Z</lastModified>
  <excerpt />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Gist: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap.js depends on &lt;a href="http://jquery.com/" target="_blank"&gt;jQuery v1.7&lt;/a&gt; or higher. The current ASP.NET MVC4 template installs jQuery v1.6.2.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Long Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;After successfully creating my MVC 4 application, adding a Cloud Service project, successfully configuring, publishing and testing my new cloudapp deployment to Windows Azure, all of my bits in place right? Not so fast.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Today, if I am not rolling out a custom &lt;a href="http://orchardproject.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Orchard CMS&lt;/a&gt; build, then I will typically use &lt;a href="http://html5boilerplate.com/" target="_blank"&gt;HTML5 Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; as the site design templates of choice. Primarily because as a LOB developer, I’m not so much a designer and so any assets along these lines makes for a great day of work for me.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;For my current project, I decided on Twitter Bootstrap and after porting the layout and styles to the _Layout.cshtml file I thought that I was ready to rock. However, each time that I ran the application, I was presented with the following error message:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bacardibryant.com/Posts/files/bootstrapError_636829313373861055.png"&gt;&lt;img title="bootstrapError" style="border-width: 0px; padding-top: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-left: 0px; display: inline; background-image: none;" border="0" alt="bootstrapError" src="http://www.bacardibryant.com/Posts/files/bootstrapError_thumb_636829313381990223.png" width="534" height="307" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In essence, “Object doesn’t support property or method ‘on’”. Because I’ve become so accustomed to jQuery dependencies working out of the box, it didn’t immediately occur to me that there could be a jQuery version issue. So I spent some time debugging and tweaking my code, thinking that perhaps I didn’t quite bundle the scripts correctly or something like that. After about an two hours with no success, I decided to “bingit!” (yes, I actually do use Bing). I found the &lt;a href="https://github.com/twitter/bootstrap/issues/2169" target="_blank"&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt; that I needed right in the twitter/bootstrap forum on github. The gist: &lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap.js depends on &lt;a href="http://jquery.com/" target="_blank"&gt;jQuery v1.7&lt;/a&gt; or higher.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;While this was an easy fix and &lt;a href="http://www.markdotto.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Mark Otto&lt;/a&gt; (creator of Bootstrap) has done an awesome job with the platform, I still think that it would be cool to add a note somewhere on the project homepage of its dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bacardibryant.com/Posts/files/bootstrapHomePage_636829313384757077.png"&gt;&lt;img title="bootstrapHomePage" style="border-width: 0px; padding-top: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-left: 0px; display: inline; background-image: none;" border="0" alt="bootstrapHomePage" src="http://www.bacardibryant.com/Posts/files/bootstrapHomePage_thumb_636829313386782252.png" width="541" height="232" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Get it to the cloud…fast!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>true</ispublished>
  <categories>
    <category>programming</category>
  </categories>
  <comments></comments>
</post>